Guide to the Robert L. McCaul, Jr. Papers 1900-1994
University of Chicago Library
- Series V: Writings and Speeches
  - Struggle for Schooling: The Effort to Win Public-School Rights for Illinois Blacks, 1800-1875 – Chapters 1 and 2 – Photocopies of Typescript (Later The Black Struggle for Public Schooling in Nineteenth Century Illinois), undated (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Struggle for Schooling: The Effort to Win Public-School Rights for Illinois Blacks, 1800-1875 – Chapter 3 – Photocopies of Typescript (Later The Black Struggle for Public Schooling in Nineteenth Century Illinois), undated (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Struggle for Schooling: The Effort to Win Public-School Rights for Illinois Blacks, 1800-1875 – Chapter 5 – Photocopies of Typescript (Later The Black Struggle for Public Schooling in Nineteenth Century Illinois), undated (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Struggle for Schooling: The Effort to Win Public-School Rights for Illinois Blacks, 1800-1875 – Chapter 6 – Photocopies of Typescript (Later The Black Struggle for Public Schooling in Nineteenth Century Illinois), undated (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Struggle for Schooling: The Effort to Win Public-School Rights for Illinois Blacks, 1800-1875 – Chapter 7 – Photocopies of Typescript (Later The Black Struggle for Public Schooling in Nineteenth Century Illinois), undated (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Struggle for Schooling: The Effort to Win Public-School Rights for Illinois Blacks, 1800-1875 – Chapters 8 and 9– Photocopies of Typescript (Later The Black Struggle for Public Schooling in Nineteenth Century Illinois), undated (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Struggle for Schooling: The Effort to Win Public-School Rights for Illinois Blacks, 1800-1875 – Appendix – Photocopies of Typescript (Later The Black Struggle for Public Schooling in Nineteenth Century Illinois), undated (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Student Forum Remarks – Typescripts, 1966 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - "Twentieth-Century Books influencing American Education" (Various Titles) – Typescripts, Journals, Correspondence, 1970-1976 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Unidentified Book – Index – Typescript with Corrections, undated (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Unidentified Chapter I – History of High School – Typescript, Manuscript, Source Material, undated (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - "Whitefield's Bethesda College Projects and Other Major Attempts to Found Colonial Colleges" – Part I – Journals, 1960 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - "Whitefield's Bethesda College Projects and Other Major Attempts to Found Colonial Colleges" – Part II – Journals, Indices, Typescript, 1960 (Box 28, Folder 11)
- Series VI: Microfilm
  - Microfilm, undated (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Photographs – Robert McCaul, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 13)
- Series VII: Restricted
  - Journal – April, 1963, 1991 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Journal – May, 1963, 1962-1963 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Journal – June, 1963 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Journal – July, 1963 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Journal – August, 1963 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Journal – September, 1963 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Journal – October, 1963 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Journal –November, 1963 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Journal – December, 1963 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Journal – January, 1964 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Journal – February, 1964 [1 of 2] (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Journal – February, 1964 [2 of 2] (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Journal – March 1964 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Journal – April, 1964 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Journal – May, 1964 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Journal – June, 1964 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Journal – July, 1964 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Journal – August-September, 1964 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Journal – October, 1964 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Journal – November, 1964 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Journal – December, 1964 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Journal – January, 1965 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Journal Carbons – January, 1965 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Journal – February, 1965 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Journal Carbons – February, 1965 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Journal – March, 1965 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Journal Carbons – March, 1965 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Journal – April, 1965 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Journal Carbons – April, 1965 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Journal – May, 1965 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Journal Carbons – May, 1965 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Journal – June, 1965 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Journal Carbons – June, 1965 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Journal – July, 1965 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Journal Carbons – July, 1965 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Journal – August, 1965 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Journal – September, 1965 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Journal Carbons – August-September, 1965 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Journal – October, 1965 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Journal Carbons – October, 1965 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Journal – November, 1965 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Journal Carbons – November, 1965 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Journal – December, 1965 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Journal Carbons – December, 1965 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Journal – January, 1966 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Journal – February, 1966 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Journal – March, 1966 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Journal – April, 1966 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Journal – May, 1966 [1 of 2] (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Journal – May, 1966 [2 of 2] (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Journal – June, 1966 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Journal – July, 1966 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Journal – August, 1966 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Journal – September, 1966 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Journal – October, 1966 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Journal – November, 1966 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Journal – December, 1966 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Journal – January, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Journal – February, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Journal – March, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Journal – April, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Journal – May, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Journal – June, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Journal – July, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Wentz, Robert – Dissertation Proposal with Notes, 1967 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Letters of Recommendation, 1969-1975 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Student Grades, 1971-1977 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Letters of Recommendation, 1976-1979 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Letters of Recommendation, 1980-1984 (Box 38, Folder 5)